Was it all just a dream?
所有這一起只是一場夢嗎？
God bless you, Florida! Thank you!
上帝保佑佛羅里達！謝謝你們！
Did the last four years not really happen?
過去四年這些事情真的未發生過嗎？
Look, there's Ben Affleck. He's often in my dreams.
看，那是本﹒阿弗萊克 我做夢的時候老夢到他
And the T axi Driver guy. He was there too.
還有演《出租汽車司機》的那個家伙 （指羅伯特﹒德尼羅），他也在那
And little Stevie Wonder, he seemed so happy...
還有小史蒂夫.王德爾， 他看起來很高興
...like a miracle had taken place.
像是有奇跡在發生
Was it a dream?
這是一場夢？
We want Gore!
我們要戈爾！
Or was it real?
還是一個現實？
It was election night 2000, and things seemed to be going as planned.
這是2000年大選之夜， 一切似乎在按部就班地進行
In New York, Al Gore is our projected winner.
在紐約州，預選結果戈爾勝出
The Garden State is green for Gore.
戈爾也在新澤西州一路綠燈
We project Mr. Gore the winner in Delaware. This state has voted with...
我們預計戈爾是特拉華州的勝者， 該州投票結果顯示勝者是…
Excuse me, one second. I'm sorry to interrupt.
抱歉，就一會，很抱歉打斷你們
Mike, I wouldn't do this if it weren't big.
如果不是情況重大，我不會這么做
Florida goes for Al Gore.
戈爾在佛羅里達勝出
CNN announces that we call Florida in the Al Gore column.
CNN宣布，艾爾﹒戈爾在佛州勝出
Then something called the Fox News Channel called the election...
同時，有個叫福克斯新聞頻道的 稱另一個家伙在選舉中…
...in favor of the other guy.
….形式更好
Fox News now projects George W. Bush the winner in Florida...
福克斯新聞台預計 喬治﹒華盛頓﹒布什是佛羅里達州的勝者…
...and thus it appears the winner of the presidency of the United States.
….這樣似乎他就將在美國總統大選中勝出
All of a sudden, the other networks said:
突然，另一個新聞網宣布：
"Hey, if Fox said it, it must be true."
“嘿，如果福克斯這么說，那么就是真的啦”
All of us at the networks made a mistake...
我們整個新聞網都錯誤地…
...and projected Florida in the Al Gore column.
….預計了戈爾是佛羅里達州的勝者
It was our mistake.
這是我們的失誤
What most people don't know is that the man in charge...
大多數人不知道的是， 當天晚上在福克斯台…
...of the decision desk at Fox that night...
拍板為布什造勢的…
...the man who called it for Bush...
不是別人…
...was none other than Bush's first cousin John Ellis.
正是布什的表兄約翰﹒埃利斯
How does someone like Bush get away with something like this?
這些人比如說布什，怎么來澄清下列事實？
Well, first, it helps if your brother is the governor of the state in question.
首先，如果你弟弟在投票存疑的州任州長 這可能有好處
You know something? We are gonna win Florida. Mark my words.
知道嗎？我們將會在佛羅里達州獲勝 記住我的話
You can write it down.
你可以寫下來
Second, make sure your campaign chairman...
其次，要知道， 你競選團的主席
...is also the vote-count woman and that her state hires a company...
同時也是個管計票的女人 而且她所在的州請了個公司…
...to knock voters off the rolls who aren't likely to vote for you.
把那些可能不會投你票的人 從選民冊上划掉
You can usually tell them by the color of their skin.
你可以從膚色上辨別這些（被划掉的）人
Then make sure your side fights like it's life or death.
然后讓你那邊人拚死拚活也要贏得選戰
This talk about legitimacy is overblown.
關于選舉合法性的議論有些過分了
President Bush! President Bush!
布什是總統！布什是總統！
And hope the other side sits by.
并且希望對手也只是坐等電話鈴響 （畫面上這兩位是國會民主黨領袖）
And even if numerous independent investigations...
即使無數的獨立調查顯示…
...prove that Gore got the most votes...
….戈爾贏得了大多數選票
If there was a statewide recount, Gore won the election.
如果全國范圍內每處都重新計票， 戈爾將贏得選舉
...it won't matter, as long as all your daddy's friends...
….但沒關系，只要你老爹的朋友們…
...on the Supreme Court vote the right way.
…在最高法院作出公正的定奪即可
While I strongly disagree with the court's decision, I accept it.
雖然我強烈不同意法院的決定， 我還是接受它
What we need now is acceptance.
我們現在需要的，只是接受
We have a new president-elect.
我們有了一個新當選的總統
It turns out none of this was a dream. It's what really happened.
結果這終于不是一場夢 這些都真的發生了
On the day the joint session of both the House of Representatives...
終于到了參眾兩院聯合會議…
...and the Senate was to certify the election results...
…確認選舉結果的那一天
...AI Gore, in his dual role as outgoing vice president...
艾爾﹒戈爾，以即將卸任的副總統…
...and president of the Senate...
….和參議院主席的雙重身份
...presided over the event that would officially anoint...
…主持了這場正式任命喬治﹒布什
...George W. Bush as the new president.
….為總統的儀式
If any congressman wanted to raise an objection, the rules insisted...
如果任何一個眾議員要提出異議， 規則規定
...that he or she had to have the signed support of just one senator.
他或她只需要有一個參議員來 聯合署名以示支持
Mr. President, and I take great pride in calling you that...
主席先生，很榮幸地通告您…
...I must object because of the overwhelming evidence...
…我必須提出異議， 因為選舉行為失當、有意舞弊以及…
...of misconduct, deliberate fraud and an attempt to suppress voter...
試圖對投票人施加壓力的証據 是如此不容忽視
The chair must remind members that under Section 18 of Title 3...
主席必須提醒各位，憲法第18章第3條規定
...United States Code, no debate is allowed in the joint session.
在聯合會議上禁止辯論
Thank you, Mr. President. To answer your question...
謝謝，主席先生 對您問題的回答是：
...the objection is in writing, signed by a number of members...
…書面的異議書已草擬，并有 若干眾議員的簽名…
...of the House of Representatives, but not by a member of the Senate.
….但沒有參議員聯署
Mr. President, it is in writing and signed by several House colleagues...
主席先生，它已書面草就，并 有几位眾議院同僚的署名…
...on behalf, and myself, of the 27,000 voters of Duval County...
….以代表我自己和杜瓦爾縣的2.7萬投票人
...in which 16,000 of them are African-Americans...
….他們中的1.6萬非洲裔美國人
...that was disenfranchised in this last election.
….在最近的選舉中被剝奪了公民權
Is the objection signed by a member of the Senate?
該異議書有參議員署名嗎？
Not signed by a member of the Senate.
沒有被參議員署名
The Senate is missing.
參議員沒有了
It is in writing and signed by myself...
它以書面草就，我代表
...on behalf of many of the diverse constituents...
許多異議者署名
...especially those in the 9th Congressional District...
尤其是第九選區的…
...and all American voters who recognize that the Supreme Court...
所有的美國投票人都認為是最高法院…
...not the people of the United States, decided this election.
而不是美國人民決定了選舉
Is the objection signed by a senator?
異議書有參議員署名嗎？
Unfortunately, Mr. President, it is not signed by one single senator.
主席先生，不幸的是，沒有任何一個 參議員署名
I have no authority over the United States Senate...
我沒有蓋過參議院的權力…
...and no senator has signed.
….于是沒有參議員署名
Mr. President, it is in writing and signed by myself and several...
主席先生，它已書面擬好，并且 有我和几位來自佛羅里達州的…
...of my constituents from Florida. A senator is needed, but missing.
…委托人的簽名，需要有一位 參議員署名，但沒有
Is the objection in writing...
它是書面的，并且…
...and signed by a member of the House and a senator?
有參議員署名嗎？
The objection is in writing, and I don't care...
異議書是書面的，我才不管…
...that it is not signed by a member of the Senate.
…它有沒有參議員署名
The chair will advise that the rules do care...
主席建議，規則確實規定…
...and the signature of a senator...
….需要參議員的署名…
Not a single senator came to the aid of the African-Americans in Congress.
沒有一位參議員為國會里的非洲裔美國人助陣
One after another, they were told to sit down and shut up.
一個接一個，他們被告知:坐下，肅靜
It's a sad day in America, Mr. President, when we can't find...
主席先生，這是美國史上悲哀的一天…
...a senator to sign the objections...
….沒有一個參議員在異議書上署名
- The gentleman will suspend... - New Democratic senators won't sign.
這位先生請停止發言
Inauguration coverage, 2001...
2001年就職典禮那天…
...on a nasty, but it could be worse, kind of day in Washington.
…華盛頓天氣有几分陰霾, 但還有更糟的…
- What do we want? - Justice!
我們要什么？ 公正！
- When do we want it? - Now!
何時要！ 就現在!
On the day George W. Bush was inaugurated...
在布什就職當天…
...tens of thousands of Americans poured into the streets of D. C...
成千上萬美國人涌上華盛頓街頭…
...in one last attempt to reclaim what had been taken from them.
再一次申張他們被剝奪的權利
They pelted Bush's limo with eggs...
他們向布什的座車投雞蛋
Stay back! Get back!
退后！退后！
...and brought the inauguration parade to a halt.
使得就職游行一度中止
The plan to have Bush get out of the limo for the traditional walk...
布什下車循舊例步行前往白宮的
...to the White House was scrapped.
計划也被取消
Bush's limo hit the gas to prevent an even larger riot.
布什的座車加速逃走 以避免更大的騷亂
No president had ever witnessed such a thing on his inauguration day.
從未有總統在就職典禮上 見過這種場面
And for the next eight months, it didn't get any better for George W. Bush.
接下來的八個月內 布什的處境也未好轉
He couldn't get his judges appointed, he struggled to pass his legislation...
他遲遲未能任命最高法官， 他要費盡九牛二虎之力讓法令通過
...and he lost Republican control of the Senate.
他還讓共和黨失掉了對參院的控制
His approval ratings in the polls began to sink.
他的支持率也開始下滑
He was already beginning to look like a lame-duck president.
他已經看上去像一個競選失敗就要 卸任的總統了
With everything going wrong, he did what any of us would do.
所有的事情都一團糟 他使出了我們都會的一招
He went on vacation.
他跑去休假了
Oh, no!
噢，糟！
In his first eight months in office before September 11th...
在911之前的八個月里
...George W. Bush was on vacation, according to The Washington Post...
根據《華盛頓郵報》統計
...42 percent of the time.
布什有42％的時間在度假
If I hit every shot good, people would say I wasn't working.
如果我每杆都打好了，人們會說 我沒好好工作
It was not surprising that Mr. Bush needed some time off.
布什先生要消磨掉一些時間， 這也沒什么大驚小怪的啦
Being president is a lot of work.
做總統活兒當然多啦
What about these folks that say that you're taking too long of a vacation?
對那些說您度假太多的人您怎么看？
They don't understand the definition of work, then.
他們不明白工作的定義是什么
I'm getting a lot done. You don't have to be in Washington to work.
我手頭一直有不少事在做啊 不一定非得到華盛頓去做吧
It's amazing what can happen with telephones and faxes.
用電話和傳真辦起事來很帶勁的
Thank you so much.
多謝了
- Is this to Destiny and Bubba? - Yeah.
這是給戴思婷和杜芭的嗎？ 嗯
What are you doing the rest of the day?
白天你剩下的時間在做什么呢？
Karen Hughes is coming over. We're working on some things.
凱倫﹒休斯要過來， 我們一起有些事要辦
And she'll be over here. We're working on a few things, a few matters.
她要來這兒，我們有一些 事情，一些問題要處理
I'm working on some initiatives. We're... You'll see.
知道嗎，我有些議案要處理 我們…
There'll be some decisions I will have made while I'm here.
有些決策我得在這里做
We'll be announcing them as time goes on.
時機合適我們就會宣布的
The first time I met him, he had some good advice for me.
我首次見到他的時候，他給了 我一些不錯的點子
Governor Bush, it's Michael Moore.
布什州長，我是麥克﹒摩爾
Behave yourself, will you? Go find real work.
你老實點行嗎？ 去找點正經工作做
And work was something he knew a lot about.
他對工作可是很在行的
- Anybody want some grits? - Yeah.
還有人要玉米粉嗎？ 有
Relaxing at Camp David. Yachting off Kennebunkport.
在戴維營休養 在肯尼特港附近玩游艇
How you doing?
你怎么了？
Or being a cowboy on the ranch in Texas.
或者在德州的牧場當牛仔
I love nature, getting in the truck with my dogs.
我喜歡大自然，和 我的狗一起坐卡車
Oh, hi.
噢，嗨
George Bush spent the rest of August at the ranch...
八月份剩下那些日子布什消磨在牧場上了
...where life was less complicated.
比起來，那里的生活不那么棘手難纏
Armadillos love to dig the soil looking for bugs.
犰狳喜歡在地上打洞找臭虫
And...
還有…
So I went out there the other day, and there was Barney...
我前几天來這里的時候，巴尼…
...buried in this hole, chasing an armadillo.
正撅在洞里捉犰狳呢
It was a summer to remember.
這是個值得紀念的夏天
Afterward, he left Texas for his second-favorite place.
后天，在9月10日， 他離開德州前往他第二喜歡的地方
On September 10th, he joined his brother in Florida...
….佛羅里達，去和他弟弟會合
...where they looked at files and met important Floridians.
他在那里調閱了些文件， 并且和佛州一些大人物會面
He went to sleep that night in a bed made with fine French linens.
當晚他睡在上好的法國亞麻織成的床上
Do you suppose he's pretty confident...
你覺得他對伊拉克安全部隊
...on those numbers on Iraqi security forces?
的數字很有信心嗎？ （畫面上此人是國防部長拉姆斯費爾德）
Make me look young.
這讓我看起來年輕些 （此人是司法部長阿什克羅夫特）
Yeah, I've got a little, sort of air noise.
無線耳機里有些小小的噪音
Yeah, just don't turn it up too much. I don't want to blow my head off.
嗯，不要把音量調太大 我可不想把腦袋炸掉
I got a mike here if they want to use it.
如果他們要用的話 我這里有麥克風
Testing, one, two. This is the Oval Office. Testing, one, two.
測試中，1，2 這是總統辦公室，測試中，1，2
Testing, one, two. This is the Oval Office.
這是總統辦公室
Testing, one, two, three, four, five.
測試中，1，2
We have something that has happened here...
我們發現世貿中心這里 出了些狀況
...at the World Trade Center. We noticed a flame...
我們注意到有火光和
...and an awful lot of smoke...
多得可怕的濃煙
This is horrible.
太恐怖了
- Oh, my God! - Oh, my God.
噢，上帝！
Oh, my, dear.
噢，親愛的
Let's go! Let's go, back! Come on, let's go!
快走，快走，退后！ 怪，跟上！
Oh, my God!
噢，上帝啊
Save their souls, Lord.
主啊，拯救他們的靈魂吧
Oh, they're jumping.
噢，他們在跳樓
On September 11th, 2001, nearly 3000 people...
2001年，9月11日， 近3000人
...including a colleague of mine, Bill Weems...
包括我的一位同事 比爾﹒威姆斯
...were killed in the largest foreign attack ever on American soil.
在外國人對美國本土有史以來最大的 襲擊事件中喪生
The targets were the financial and military headquarters...
襲擊的目標是美國的…
...of the United States.
商業和軍事心臟
If anyone has any idea or they've seen him or knows where he is, to call us.
如果有人見過他 或者知道他在哪，請給我們打電話
He's got two little babies. Two little babies.
他有兩個小寶寶 兩個小寶寶
As the attack took place, Mr. Bush was on his way...
當襲擊發生的時候， 布什正在去往
...to an elementary school in Florida.
佛州一所小學的路上
When informed of the first plane hitting the World Trade Center...
當被告知8年前就被恐怖分子攻擊 過的世貿中心
...where terrorists had struck just eight years prior...
正遭到第一架飛機攻擊的時候
...Mr. Bush decided to go ahead with his photo opportunity.
布什決定讓新聞記者的拍照時間繼續下去
- Good morning, boys and girls. - Good morning.
孩子們，早上好！ 早上好
Read this word the fast way. Get ready.
快速讀一下這個詞 准備
- "Mad"! - Yes. Get ready.
“MAD” 好，准備
- "Calf"! - Yeah.
“Calf”! 好
Get ready to read the words on this page without making a mistake.
准備讀這一頁的詞 不要犯錯
When the second plane hit the tower...
當第二架飛機撞上了雙塔時
...his chief of staff entered the classroom...
他的白宮辦公廳主任進入到教室里
...and told Mr. Bush, "The nation is under attack."
告訴布什先生： “國家正遭到攻擊”
Not knowing what to do, with no one telling him what to do...
他不知道該怎么辦 因為沒人告訴他該怎么辦
...and no Secret Service rushing in to take him to safety...
沒有特工人員沖進來把 他帶到安全地點
...Mr. Bush just sat there...
布什先生只是坐在那兒
...and continued to read My Pet Goat with the children.
繼續給孩子們朗讀 《我的寵物山羊》
Nearly seven minutes passed with nobody doing anything.
近7分鐘過去了 沒有任何人有所行動
As Bush sat in that Florida classroom...
當布什坐在佛州教室中的時候
...was he wondering if maybe he should have shown up...
他是否正在思忖要是他在工作上
...to work more often?
多費點心思就好了呢？
Should he have held at least one meeting since taking office...
要是在上任以來，至少和反恐官員
...to discuss the threat of terrorism with his head of counterterrorism?
開一次討論恐怖威脅的會議就好了？
Maybe Bush wondered why he had cut terrorism funding from the FBI.
也許布什在想為什么他要削減掉 聯邦調查局的反恐經費
Or perhaps he just should have read the security briefing...
或者他也許本應該看看2001年8月6日
...that was given to him on August 6th, 2001...
呈上來的安全簡報
...which said Osama bin Laden was planning...
那里面說，奧薩瑪﹒本拉登正計划
...to attack America by hijacking airplanes.
劫機攻擊美國
Maybe he wasn't worried, because the title of the report was too vague.
也許是因為報告的標題太含混 他才沒有放在心上吧
I believe the title was "Bin Laden Determined...
我記得標題是
...to Attack Inside the United States."
“本﹒拉登決心在美國國內發動襲擊”
A report like that might make some men jump...
這樣一份報告也許能夠嚇人一跳
...but, as in days past, George W. Just went fishing.
但是，時間流逝 喬治只是繼續釣著魚
As the minutes went by, George Bush continued to sit in the classroom.
時間一分一秒地過去， 喬治﹒布什仍還坐在教室里
Was he thinking, "I've been hanging out with the wrong crowd.
他是否在想我是不是一直 和一堆壞人混在一起？
Which one of them screwed me?
他們中哪一個糊弄了我呢？
Was it the guy my daddy's friends delivered a lot of weapons to?
是我老爸賣給他不少軍火的那個家伙？ （畫面上是1983年的拉姆斯費爾德和薩達姆）
Was it that group of religious fundamentalists...
還是在我當州長的時候，跑到州里參觀
...who visited my state when I was governor?
的那幫原教旨宗教團？
Or was it the Saudis?
或者是那個沙特人？
Damn. It was them. I think I better blame it on this guy."
媽的，就是這幫人， 我最好怪罪到這個家伙身上
In the days following September 11th...
911之后的第二天
...all commercial and private airline traffic was grounded.
所有的商業和私人航班全部停飛
The FAA has taken the action to close all of the airports in the United States.
聯邦航空局關閉了美國境內所有的機場
Even grounding the president's father, former President Bush...
即使是總統的父親也落地了，前總統布什
...on a flight forced to land in Milwaukee.
乘坐的航班在密爾沃基州被迫降落了
Thousands of travelers were stranded, among them Ricky Martin...
數以千計的乘客束手無策 里奇﹒馬丁是其中之一
...due to appear at tonight's Latin Grammy Awards.
他本來應在當晚的拉丁格萊美獎上露面的
Not even Ricky Martin could fly. But really, who wanted to fly?
即使是里奇﹒馬丁也無法飛起來 而實際上，誰又愿意飛起來呢？
No one, except the bin Ladens.
一個人也沒有，除了本﹒拉登們
We had airplanes pick up...
我們的飛機載著本﹒拉登的家族和 （此人是參議員航空委員會主席）
...Osama bin Laden's family and other Saudis...
其他沙特人
...and transport them out of the U.S.
將他們運出了美國
The White House approved planes...
白宮批准航班可以搭載
...to pick up the bin Ladens and numerous other Saudis.
本﹒拉登們和不少其他沙特人
At least six private jets and nearly two dozen commercial planes...
至少有六架私人飛機和近兩打的商業航班
...carried the Saudis and bin Ladens...
在9月13日后載著本﹒拉登們和其他沙特人
...out of the U. S. After September 13th.
飛出了美國
In all, 142 Saudis, including 24 members of the bin Laden family...
總計有142個沙特人，包括24個本﹒拉登的族人
...were allowed to leave the country.
被允許離開美國
Osama's always been portrayed as the black sheep in the family...
奧薩瑪﹒本﹒拉登一直被描述成家族里的 害群之馬
...that they cut off all relationship with him in 1994.
他們在1994年就和他斷了一切往來
It's more complicated than that.
實情遠比這復雜
Osama has had contact with other family members?
奧薩瑪和其他族人一直有交往嗎？
Right. In the summer of 2001, just before 9/11, one of Osama's sons...
沒錯，在2001年夏天，正好在911之前， 奧薩瑪的兒子
...got married in Afghanistan, and several family members...
在阿富汗結婚了，好几個家族成員
...showed up at the wedding. - Bin Ladens?
都出現在了婚禮上 都是本拉登家的？
That's right. So they're not cut off completely. That's an exaggeration.
沒錯，所以他們并未完全斷絕往來 那是夸大之辭
We now welcome to Larry King Live...
歡迎收看拉里﹒金的直播節目
...Prince Bandar, ambassador of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to the U.S.
班達王子是沙特駐美大使
You had about 24 members of bin Laden's family, and...
你們有24個本﹒拉登家族的成員，并且
- Here? - In America. Students and...
在這里嗎？ 在美國，有學生和…
His Majesty felt it's not fair for those innocent people to be subjected...
陛下覺得那些無辜的人受到傷害是不公平的
...to any harm. On the other hand, we understood the high emotions...
另一方面，我們也了解美國人群情激昂
...so, with coordination with the FBI, we got them out.
所以我們和聯邦調查局合作， 把他們弄出去了
This is retired FBI agent Jack Cloonan.
這是退役的聯邦調查局探員 杰克﹒柯南
Before 9/11, he was a senior agent on the joint FBl-CIA...
在911之前，他是聯邦調查局和中情局 “基地組織聯合調查組”
...al Qaeda task force.
的高級探員
I, as an investigator, would not want these people to have left.
作為調查人員，我不愿意讓這些人離開
I think, in the case of the bin Laden family, it would have been prudent...
我認為，既然是本﹒拉登家族的， 本應當謹慎地
...to hand the subpoenas out, have them come in, get on-the-record.
開出傳票，讓他們到局里來一趟 記錄在案
You know, get on-the-record.
明白嗎，記錄在案
- That's the proper procedure? - Yeah.
這是才是合理的程序？ 是的
How many people were pulled off airlines after that...
有很多人在機場被抓了起來，為了什么？
...coming into the country who were Middle Eastern...
還不是因為他們來自中東
...or they fit a very general picture.
或者是有些像而已
We held hundreds of people for weeks and months at a time.
我們同時拘捕了數百人 關了他們几周到几個月
Did the authorities do anything when the bin Ladens tried to leave?
當本﹒拉登的族人試圖離開的時候 當局有何行動？
No. They were identified at the airport.
沒有，他們在機場被驗明了身份
They looked at their passports, and they were identified.
看過護照后，他們被驗明了身份
That would happen to us if we left the country.
如果我們出國時，也會這樣
- Exactly. - Interview, check the passport.
沒錯 問話，檢查護照
- What else? - Nothing.
還有呢？ 沒了
I don't know about you, but usually...
我不知道你們如何行動的 但通常說來…
...when the police can't find a murderer...
當警方找不到凶嫌時
...don't they usually wanna talk to the family members...
警察不是通常找到嫌犯家里的人…
...to find out where they think he might be?
問他們凶手可能在哪嗎？
You don't know where your husband is?
你不知道你丈夫在哪里？
If you hear anything, let us know.
如果你知道什么情況，要通知我們
Can you come downtown, give a statement?
你能到城里來做份筆錄嗎？
- How long? - You've got time.
這要多長時間？ 你有時間
Mine's worth money. Yours isn't.
我的時間可值錢啦，不像你們
- Send a bill. - I asked you a question.
我問你們一個問題
- Answer them. Don't ask them. - I pay your salary, cop.
是你來答問題，不是問問題 警官，你們的薪水可是我付的
Sit down. I'm gonna earn it.
坐下！
Yeah. That's how cops do it. What was going on here?
是的，這才是警察辦事的樣子 我們這里是怎么做的呢？
We need to know more about that.
我認為我們需要多了解這件事情
It needs to be the subject of an investigation.
它應該成為調查的焦點
What happened? How did it happen? Why? Who authorized it?
發生了什么，怎么發生的 為什么發生的，誰批准的
Imagine what those poor bastards were feeling...
想象一下那些可憐人的感受
...when jumping off that building to their death.
當他們跳樓摔死的時候
Those young guys and cops and firemen...
還有那些年輕人、警察和消防隊員
...that ran into that building, never asked a question.
他們沖進建筑里，從未遲疑過
And they're dead. And families' lives are ruined.
他們死了，家庭的生活給毀了
- And they'll never have peace. - That's right.
他們從未安寧過
And if I had to inconvenience...
如果我非得去傳訊本﹒拉登的族人
...a member of the bin Laden family with a subpoena or a grand jury...
當然會有傳票和陪審團
...do you think I'd lose sleep over it? Not a minute.
你覺得我會睡得不踏實嗎？一分鐘也不會
No one would question it. Not even the biggest civil libertarian.
－沒有人會質疑這種行為？－沒有 －即使是最大的主張公民自由的團體也不會？
- No, no. It's just... - No one would question it.
沒有 沒有人會質疑此事
You know, you got a lawyer? Fine. Counsel? Fine.
知道嗎，他只要有個律師或者 法律顧問就可以了，兩者都行
Mr. Bin Laden, this is why I'm asking. It isn't because I think you're anything.
我們只要問他：拉登先生，我們問你 不是因為我們覺得你做了什么
I just want to ask you the questions that I would anybody.
我只是想向你問些我可能問任何人的問題
- Right. - And that's all.
不錯 這就夠了
None of this made any sense.
但這些都沒用
Can you imagine in the days after the Oklahoma City terrorist bombing...
你還能想象一下俄克拉荷馬城爆炸案 之后的那些日子里
...President Clinton helping to arrange a trip...
克林頓總統安排
...out of the country for the McVeigh family?
麥克維（俄城爆炸案凶手）的家人出國
What would have happened to Clinton...
一旦當時事情被揭發
...if that had been revealed? - Burn him! Burn him!
克林頓將會如何？ 燒死他！燒死他！
Prince Bandar, do you know the bin Laden family?
班達王子，你認識本﹒拉登的家人嗎？
- I do, very well. - What are they like?
很熟 他們是怎樣的人
They're really lovely human beings. He is the only one I never...
他們都是很可愛的人 他是唯一一個我從未…
I don't know him well, but I met him only once.
我不太了解他，但我曾見過他一次
What was the circumstance under which you met?
你們是在何種情形下見面的？
This is ironic. In the mid-'80s...
所起來有些諷刺 那是在80年代中期
...if you remember, we and the United States...
如果你還記得的話，我們和美國
...were supporting the mujahideen...
正支持伊斯蘭游擊隊
...to liberate Afghanistan from the Soviets.
將阿富汗從蘇聯人手中解放出來
He came to thank me for my efforts to bring the Americans, our friends...
他來感謝我把美國人－我們的朋友帶過來
...to help us against the atheists, the Communists. Isn't it ironic?
幫我們反抗共產黨無神論者， 不是很諷刺嗎？
He came to thank you for helping bring America to help him.
他來感謝你把美國人帶來幫他
And now he may be responsible for bombing America.
而現在他也許要對襲擊美國的行動負責？
- Absolutely. - What did you make of him?
的確是 你對他的了解是怎樣的？
- I was not impressed. - Not impressed?
沒有印象了 沒有印象？
No. I thought he was a simple and very quiet guy.
我覺得他是個簡朴、安靜的人
A simple and quiet guy, whose family just happened to have...
一個簡朴、安靜的人， 他的家族湊巧在和
...a business relationship with the family of George W. Bush.
喬治﹒布什的家族做生意
Is that what he was thinking about?
他是在想這件事嗎？
Because if the public knew this, it wouldn't look very good.
如果公眾知道了這事，看上去恐怕不妙
Was he thinking, "You know...
他是不在想：嗯
...I need a big, black marker"?
我要不要把黑檔案給抹去點什么呢？
In early 2004, in a speech during the New Hampshire primary...
在2004年初， 在新罕布什爾州初選的一次演講中
...I called George W. Bush a deserter...
我稱布什為“逃兵”
...from his time in the Texas Air National Guard.
當年他正在德州的國民警衛隊服役
In response, the White House released his military records...
為了回應，白宮公布了 他的服役記錄
...in the hopes of disproving the charge.
希望洗脫該指控
What Bush didn't know is that I already had a copy...
布什不知道的是，我在2000年就已經弄到了 一份
...of his military records, uncensored, obtained in the year 2000.
關于他服役記錄的未經刪改的副本
And there is one glaring difference between the records released...
在2000年和2004年這兩個版本中
...in 2000 and those he released in 2004.
有一處引人注目的區別
A name had been blacked out.
有一個名字被划掉了
In 1972, two airmen were suspended for failing to take...
1972年，兩位飛行員因為未參加體檢 受到處分
...their medical examination. One was George W. Bush.
其中一位是喬治﹒布什
And the other was James R. Bath.
另一位是詹姆斯﹒巴斯
In 2000, the documents show both names.
2000年時，文件上這兩個名字都有
But in 2004, Bush and the White House had Bath's name blacked out.
但在2004年，布什和白宮將巴斯的名字划掉了
Why didn't Bush want the press and the public...
為什么布什不愿意讓媒體和公眾
...to see Bath's name on his military records?
在他的服役記錄上看到巴斯的名字呢？
Perhaps he was worried that the American people would find out...
也許他擔心美國人會發現
...that at one time, James R. Bath...
當年詹姆斯﹒巴斯是
...was the Texas money manager for the bin Ladens.
本﹒拉登家族在德州的資產托管人
Bush and Bath had become good friends...
布什和巴斯在德州國民警衛隊空軍
...when they both served in the Texas Air National Guard.
服役時一直是好友
After they were discharged...
他們退役以后
...when Bush's dad was head of the CIA...
布什的老爹當時是中情局的頭
...Bath opened up his own aviation business after selling a plane...
巴斯做起了航空生意，當他把一架飛機
...to a man by the name of Salem bin Laden...
賣給了一個叫薩勒姆﹒本﹒拉登的人
...heir to the second-largest fortune in Saudi Arabia...
他是沙特第二大財團
...the Saudi Binladin Group.
沙特本拉登集團的繼承人
W. At that time was just starting off in the world as a businessman.
喬治﹒華盛頓﹒布什當時剛剛開始 生意人生涯
Because he's a guy who's always tried to emulate his father...
因為他一直想效仿他老爸
...he went into the oil business. He founded an oil company, Arbusto...
他做起了石油生意，他成立了一家叫做 Arbusto的石油公司
...which was very good at drilling dry holes that nothing came out of.
它非常善于鑽什么油也不出的干油井
But the question has always been, "Where did this money come from?"
但是這個問題一直存在 “他的錢打哪兒來呢？”
Now, his dad was rich. His dad could have done this for him...
嗯，他老爸有錢， 他老爸本可以給他錢開公司
...but his dad didn't do this for him.
但他老爸沒有給他錢
There's no indication Daddy wrote a check to start him off in his company.
沒有証據表明他老爸給他開了支票 以啟動公司
So where did George W. Bush get his money?
那么喬治﹒布什從哪里弄到錢的呢？
I'm George Bush.
我是喬治﹒布什
One person who did invest in him was James R. Bath.
有個確實給他投資了的人叫 詹姆斯﹒巴斯
Bush's good friend, James Bath, was hired by the bin Laden family...
布什的好友巴斯，當時受雇于本﹒拉登家族
...to manage their money in Texas and invest in businesses.
以管理他們在德州的資產并進行投資
And James Bath himself, in turn, invested in George W. Bush.
詹姆斯﹒巴斯給喬治﹒布什投資
Bush ran Arbusto into the ground...
布什把Arbusto經營得很糟糕
...as he did every other company he was involved in...
他經營的每個公司都是如此
...until finally one of his companies was bought by Harken Energy...
直到后來他的一家公司 被Harken能源公司買下來
...and they gave him a seat on their board.
并在董事會里給了他一個職位
A lot of us suspected through the years that there has been...
這些年來，很多人懷疑這些公司里
...Saudi oil money involved in these companies:
有來自沙特的石油資本
Harken, Spectrum 7, Arbusto Drilling, all the Bush companies.
Harken，Spectrum 7，Arbusto Drilling，所有這些布什的公司
Whenever they got in trouble, there were these angel investors...
一旦遇到麻煩，總會有神仙一樣的投資者
...who flowed money into the companies.
往這些公司里注資
The question is, why would Saudis, who had all the oil in the world...
問題是，為什么擁有那么多石油的沙特人
...go around the globe to invest in this lousy oil company?
要跨過整個地球 跑來給這個爛石油公司投資？
And the thing is, Harken had one big thing going for it...
事實在于，Harken公司有個重大情況是
...which is that George W. Bush was on its board of directors...
喬治﹒布什是董事會成員
...at a time when his father was president of the United States.
而當時他父親是美國總統
When you're the president's son and you've got unlimited access...
當你總統的兒子的時候，你就能弄到 無數的許可權
...combined with some credentials from a prior campaign...
還有參與在華盛頓舉辦的重大活動的資格
...in Washington, D.C., people tend to respect that. Access is power.
人們會關注這個的，許可就是力量
And I can find my dad and talk to him any time of the day.
我可以在一天中的任何時候找到 爸爸并和他交談
Yes, it helps to be the president's son...
是的，當總統的兒子總會有好處
...especially when you're being investigated...
尤其是你正遭到
...by the Securities and Exchange Commission.
証券交易委員會調查的時候
In 1990, when Mr. Bush was a director of Harken Energy...
1990年，當布什還是Harken能源公司 董事時
...he received this memo from company lawyers...
他接到公司律師的備忘錄
...warning directors not to sell stock if they had...
警告董事們如果得知有關 公司的不利消息話
...unfavorable information about the company.
不要拋售股票
One week later, he sold $848,000 worth of Harken stock.
一周以后，他賣掉了價值848000美元的 Harken公司的股票
Two months later, Harken announced losses of more than $23 million.
兩個月后，Harken宣布虧本超過 2300萬美元
The James Baker law partner who helped Bush...
當時幫助布什擺平來自
...beat the rap from the SEC...
証交會質詢的律師是詹姆斯﹒貝克的合伙人
...was a man by the name of Robert Jordan...
名叫羅伯特﹒喬丹
...who, when George W. Became president...
當喬治﹒布什成為總統后
...was appointed ambassador to Saudi Arabia.
他被任命為駐沙特大使
After the Harken debacle, the friends of Bush's dad got him a seat...
在Harken公司倒閉后，布什老爹的朋友幫 他另一個在
...on another board, of a company owned by the Carlyle Group.
卡萊爾集團旗下 的公司的董事會弄到了職位
We looked at which companies gained from September 11 th.
我們看看什么公司從911里頭獲得了好處 （畫面上此人為作家）
We turned up this company, Carlyle Group, a multinational conglomerate...
我們看看這家公司，卡萊爾集團， 它是個跨國財團
...that invests in heavily government-regulated industries...
在政府管制的一些行業里 投下了巨資
...like telecommunications, health care and particularly, defense.
比如通訊、衛生保健，還有特別是 防務
Both George W. Bush and George H.W. Bush...
布什父子都為卡萊爾集團工作過
...worked for the Carlyle Group, the same company that counted...
本﹒拉登家族也恰恰是這家公司的
...the bin Laden family among its investors.
投資人之一
The Carlyle Group was holding its annual investor conference...
9月11日早晨，卡萊爾集團當時在
...on the morning of September 11th...
華盛頓的里茲卡爾頓大飯店舉行
...in the Ritz-Carlton Hotel in Washington D.C.
投資者年會
At that meeting were all of the Carlyle regulars...
會議上全是卡萊爾的鐵杆主顧
...James Baker, likely John Major, definitely George H.W. Bush...
詹姆斯﹒貝克、梅杰， 還有老布什
...though he left the morning of September 11th.
雖然當天上午他就離開了
Shafiq bin Laden, who is Osama bin Laden's half brother...
奧薩瑪﹒本﹒拉登的異母兄弟 薩費克﹒本﹒拉登
...was in town to look after his family's investments in the Carlyle Group.
也在城里照看家族在 卡萊爾集團的生意
All of them together in one room, watching...
當飛機撞上雙塔時
...as the planes hit the towers.
他們都在一個房間里看直播
In fact, the bin Laden family was invested...
事實上，本﹒拉登的家族
...in one of their defense funds, which ironically meant...
在其中的一個防務子公司中有投資 諷刺的是，這意味著
...that as the U.S. Increased defense spending, the bin Laden family...
如果美國提高防務開支，那么 本﹒拉登家族
...stood to gain from those investments through the Carlyle Group.
就將通過他們在卡萊爾集團的投資獲利
Our commander in chief, President George W. Bush.
歡迎三軍總司令 喬治﹒布什總統
With all the weapons companies it owned...
把卡萊爾集團旗下所有的軍火公司
...the Carlyle Group was, in essence, the 11th largest...
都算在一起，卡萊爾集團實際上是
...defense contractor in the United States.
美國第11大軍火提供商
- Thanks a lot. - It owned United Defense...
它擁有聯合防務（United Defense）公司 （即畫面上的這家公司）
...makers of the Bradley armored fighting vehicle.
它是布拉德利戰車的制造商
September 11th guaranteed that United Defense...
911確保了聯合防務公司
...was going to have a very good year.
又有了一個好年頭
Just six weeks after 9/11...
911之后僅僅6周
...Carlyle filed to take United Defense public...
卡萊爾集團申請將聯合防務上市售股
...and made a one-day profit of $237 million.
一天之內賺了2.37個億
But sadly, with so much attention focused...
但是不幸的是，公眾的注意力是如此
...on the bin Laden family being important Carlyle investors...
集中在本﹒拉登家族是卡萊爾集團的 重要投資人上
...the bin Ladens eventually had to withdraw.
以致最后本﹒拉登家不得不逐漸撤資
Bush's dad, though, stayed on as senior adviser...
布什的老爸任接著給
...to Carlyle's Asia board for another two years.
卡萊爾集團的亞洲理事會當了兩年 的高級顧問
As unseemly as it seems to know that George H.W. Bush...
看上去不體面的是，在911事件的很久以前
...was meeting with the bin Laden family...
奧薩瑪﹒本﹒拉登就是個被通緝的恐怖分子
...while Osama was a wanted terrorist, well before September 11 th...
而老布什還一直和本﹒拉登家族交往
...it's very discomforting for Americans to know that.
這讓美國人非常不安
George H.W. Bush is a man who has, obviously, incredible reach...
很顯然，老布什是個對白宮
...into the White House.
有著難以置信的影響力的人
He receives daily CIA briefings, which is the right of any ex-president...
他能看到中情局的每日簡報 當然前總統都有這個權力
...but very few ex-presidents actually exercise that right. He does.
但只有寥寥几個前總統實際上行使過這個權力 他是其中之一
And, I think, in a very real way they are benefiting from the confusion...
而且，我認為，當老布什
...that arises when George H.W. Bush visits Saudi Arabia...
代表卡萊爾集團訪問沙特并與
...on behalf of Carlyle and meets with the royal family...
沙特王室和本拉登家族會面時
...and meets with the bin Laden family.
有人實際上能從這個亂局中獲利
Is he representing the United States of America?
他是代表美國呢
Or is he representing an investment firm in the United States?
還是代表美國的某個財團？
Or is he representing both?
還是都代表了？
This company is about money, not conspiracies to run the world...
這個公司是只管賺錢的， 不是關心世界局勢該如何操控的
...or engineer political maneuvering and things like that.
或者是進行政治操作之類的東西
It's about making money, and it's about making a lot of money.
它只管賺錢，一大筆錢
And they've done very well.
而且他們干得很不錯
I could get you on-the-record on this question.
關于這個問題，您的回答我將會錄下來 （畫面上這個人當時是白宮發言人）
In the White House view, there is no ethical conflict...
在白宮看來，前總統布什和前國務卿貝克
...in former President Bush and former Secretary of State Jim Baker...
利用他們與各國領袖的交情
...using their contacts with world leaders to represent...
來擔任最著名的軍火商之一 的卡萊爾集團的代表
...one of the most well-known military arms dealers, the Carlyle Group?
這不會產生道德上的沖突嗎？
The president has full faith that his family will conform...
總統對這個很有信心
...with all proper ethics laws and will act properly in their conduct.
他的家人將完全遵循道德規范 并且舉止得當
Okay, let's say one group of people, like the American people...
好吧，我們來看一群人， 比如美國人
...pay you $400,000 a year to be president of the United States.
每年付給你40萬美元來做美國總統
But then another group of people invest in you, your friends...
但是另一群人，這些年來
...and their related businesses, $ 1. 4 billion over a number of years.
在你、你的朋友或是相關的生意中投資了 14億美元
Who are you gonna like? Who's your daddy?
你會喜歡誰？ 誰才是你老爸？
That's how much the Saudi royals and their associates...
那個數目就是沙特王室及其代理人
...have given the Bush family, their friends and their related businesses...
在過去30年中對布什家族、他們的朋友 以及相關生意
...in the past three decades.
投下的數目
Seems like a very nice reunion with friends.
真像是美妙的老友重逢啊
Is it rude to suggest that when the Bush family...
這么想可能有些無禮，當布什一家 早上醒來的時候
...wakes up in the morning, they might be thinking...
他們也許在想 什么對沙特人最有利
...about what's best for the Saudis instead of what's best for you or me?
而不是在想什么 對你，對我最有利
Because 1.4 billion just doesn't buy a lot of flights out of the country.
這14億美元可不是只買 很多次跨國訪問呢
It buys a lot of love.
它買了許多愛
Sooner or later, this special relationship...
這個政權違反人權的做法很普遍 （指沙特還存在酷刑等等）
...with a regime that Amnesty International condemns...
所以為大赦國際組織所譴責
...as a widespread human-rights violator...
和它之間的特殊關系
...would come back to haunt the Bushes.
遲早還會讓布什家族不得安寧
Now, after 9/11, it was an embarrassment.
在911之后，這成了令他們尷尬的事情
And they preferred that no one ask any questions.
他們希望沒有人提及這些問題
Investigation should have begun on September 12th.
調查本應在9月12日就開始了 （畫面上此人為911遇難者家屬）
There's no reason it shouldn't have. Three thousand were dead.
沒有理由當時沒開展調查 3000人遇難了，這是謀殺
It should've gotten started immediately.
本應立即開始調查
First, Bush tried to stop Congress from setting up...
首先，布什試圖阻止國會成立
...its own 9/11 investigation. - It's important for us...
它單獨的調查組 不要向敵人顯示我們是怎樣收集情報的
...to not reveal how we collect information.
這個很重要
That's what the enemy wants. And we're fighting an enemy.
那是敵人想要的，而我們正 跟敵人打仗呢
When he couldn't stop Congress, he then tried to stop...
當他阻止不了國會時，他就試圖
...an independent 9/11 commission from being formed.
阻止成立獨立的911調查委員會
The president's position was a break from history.
總統的決定歷史上從未有過先例
Independent investigations were launched after Pearl Harbor...
在珍珠港和肯尼迪暗殺事件發生后几天內
...and President Kennedy's assassination.
獨立調查就開始了
But when Congress did complete its own investigation...
但當國會真的完成了它自己的調查時
...the Bush White House censored 28 pages of the report.
白宮刪改了28頁報告
The president is being pressed by all sides to declassify the report.
各方都強烈要求總統給這份報告解密 -
U.S. Officials tell NBC News most of the secret sources...
有官員告訴NBC新聞頻道，大部分秘密都
...involve Saudi Arabia.
與沙特有關
We've given extraordinary cooperation with Chairmen Kean and Hamilton.
我們極為配合調查委員會主席基恩和漢密爾頓 的工作
We haven't gotten the materials we needed...
我們得不到所需的材料 （畫面上此人為基恩）
...and haven't gotten them in a timely fashion.
得到了也不及時， 公布報告的最后期限也耽誤了
Will you testify before the commission?
你愿意向調查委員會作証嗎？
This commission? You know, I don't... Testify? I'd be glad to visit with them.
這個委員會？你知道，我不是不愿作証， 我很愿意拜訪他們…
What it will do is, the hole that's in my heart...
我能做到的就是將這事永記心中 （畫面上此人為911遇難者遺孀）
...and has been in my heart since September 11th...
從9月11日那天起，他也一直在我心中
I lost my husband of 15 years. I am now by myself.
我失去了和我共度了１５年的丈夫 我現在孤單一人
I need to know what happened to him.
我需要知道他出了什么事
I know what I got back from the autopsy.
我知道我從解剖官那里得來的情況
That man was my life, and I have no plan.
那個人是我的生命 我不知道以后該怎么辦
I was taking a class, and they asked me...
我參加過一個心理輔導班 他們問我
...what was I gonna do in the next five years.
未來５年有什么打算
And if I'm not doing something with this, I don't know what reason...
如果我不把這事弄明白，我不知道 我還有什么理由
...I have to live. So it's very important.
活下去，這非常重要
Very important. Okay.
非常重要
Ignored by the Bush administration...
當布什當局熟視無睹時
...more than 500 relatives of 9/11 victims...
500多名911難屬
...filed suit against Saudi royals and others.
開始了對沙特王室和其他一些人的控告
The lawyers the Saudi defense minister hired...
沙特阿拉伯國防大臣雇來
...to fight the 9/11 families?
跟911難屬打官司的律師
The law firm of Bush family confidant, James A. Baker.
就來自于布什的知己－－ 詹姆士﹒貝克擁有的律師行
So right here in the center of three important American landmarks...
我現在正站在３個重要的美國地標性 建筑中
...the Watergate Hotel and office building...
水門大樓
...the Kennedy Center over there...
那邊的肯尼迪中心
...and the embassy of Saudi Arabia.
和沙特大使館
Yeah.
嗯
How much money do the Saudis have invested in America, roughly?
沙特阿拉伯在美國投資了多少錢，大致上？
I've heard figures as high as $860 billion.
我聽說大約有８千６百億
- Eight hundred and sixty billion? - Billion.
８千６百億 嗯
- That's a lot of money. - A lot, yeah.
真不少啊 是的，不少
And what percentage of our economy does that represent?
這筆錢占我們國家 經濟總量的比例是多少？
It seems like a lot.
應該不少吧
Well, in terms of investments on Wall Street in American equities...
嗯，就投在華爾街的美國股票來看
...it's roughly 6 or 7 percent of America.
大約占美國經濟總量的 6％到7％
They own a fairly good slice
他們擁有美國的很大一塊呢
Most of that money goes into the great blue-chip companies.
大部分的錢都投入到了藍籌股公司中了
Citigroup, Citibank, the largest stockholder is a Saudi.
花旗集團、花旗銀行的最大股東是沙特人
AOL-Time Warner has big Saudi investors.
美國在線和時代華納也有龐大的沙特投資
So I read where, like, the Saudis have a trillion dollars...
我曾經在哪里讀到過沙特阿拉伯在
...in our banks of their money. What would happen...
我們的銀行里有上萬億美元的存款
...if they pulled that trillion out?
如果有一天他們把這筆錢全提光，那會怎樣
A trillion dollars? That would be an enormous blow to the economy.
萬億？那一定會對經濟有巨大的沖擊
Can I speak to you for a moment, please, sir?
能打攪一會嗎？先生們？
- How are you doing? - Good, how you doing?
你好
Steve Kimball with the Secret Service. We're just ascertaining information.
我是特勤部的史蒂夫.金伯 我們只是向你確認些情況
Are you doing a documentary on the Saudi Arabian Embassy?
你們是在做有關沙特大使館的 記錄片嗎？
No. I am doing a documentary, and part of it is about Saudi Arabia.
不是，我是在做記錄片 只有一部分是關于沙特的
Even though we were nowhere near the White House...
雖然我們離白宮還很有些遠，不知為什么
...the Secret Service had shown up to ask us what we were doing...
特工卻出現了，向站在沙特阿拉伯大使館
...standing across the street from the Saudi Embassy.
馬路對面的我們質詢起來
- We're not here to cause any trouble. - Okay.
我們在這不是想惹麻煩 ok
- You know. Is that...? - No, that's fine.
好的 這沒什么問題吧
We just wanted to get some information as far as...
沒問題，我們只是想知道
What's going on, yeah.
你們在干嘛
I didn't realize the Secret Service guards foreign embassies.
我不知道特工也會守衛外國使館
- Not usually, no, sir. - No. Do they give you any trouble?
并不經常這樣 他們找過你麻煩嗎？
- Saudis? - No comment on that.
那些沙特人？ 無可奉告
Okay, I'll take that as a yes.
那我就當作是啦
Good. Thank you very much.
好，非常感謝
It turns out that Saudi Prince Bandar is perhaps...
原來沙特王子班達也許算是
...the best-protected ambassador in the U.S.
被保護得最好的駐美使節了
The U.S. State Department provides him with a six-man security detail.
美國國務院給他提供了6個 貼身安全人員
Considering how he and his family and the Saudi elite...
考慮到他和他的家族及其他沙特精英擁有
...own 7 percent of America, it's probably not a bad idea.
美國的7％，這也許不是什么壞主意
Prince Bandar was so close to the Bushes...
班達王子和布什家族關系如此密切
...they considered him a member of the family.
以致他們把他當作家族的一員
They even had a nickname for him: Bandar Bush.
他們甚至給他取了個綽號： 班達﹒布什
Two nights after September 11th, George Bush invited Bandar Bush...
911之后的第二天晚上，喬治﹒布什 邀請班達﹒布什
...over to the White House for a private dinner and a talk.
赴白宮參加私人晚宴和會談
Even though bin Laden was a Saudi...
雖然本﹒拉登是個沙特人
...and Saudi money had funded al Qaeda...
而且沙特的資金在資助基地組織
...and 15 of the 19 hijackers were Saudis...
還有19個劫機犯中的15個是沙特人
...here was the Saudi ambassador, casually dining with the president...
沙特大使還是不湊巧地在9月13日
...on September 13th.
與總統會餐
What were they talking about?
他們談了些什么呢？
Were they commiserating or comparing notes?
他們是在同病相憐還是 在合對口供？
Why would Bandar's government...
為什么班達的政府
...block American investigators from talking to the relatives...
禁止美國調查人員與那
...of the 15 hijackers?
15個劫機犯的家屬交談？
Why would Saudi Arabia become reluctant...
為什么沙特不愿凍結
...to freeze the hijackers' assets?
劫機犯們的財產？
The two of them walked out on the Truman Balcony...
他倆一起出來走到杜魯門大廳
...so that Bandar could smoke a cigar and have a drink.
以便班達能抽根雪茄并喝上一杯
In the distance, across the Potomac, was the Pentagon, partially in ruins.
不遠處，在波托馬克河對岸 是五角大樓，有一部分已成了瓦礫
I wonder if Mr. Bush told Prince Bandar not to worry...
我想知道布什總統是否 有叫班達王子不要擔心
...because he already had a plan in motion.
因為他已有了成竹在胸的計划
You come in September 12th...
9月12日
...to plot our response to al Qaeda. Let me talk about the response...
你參加了我們怎樣對付基地組織的會議 讓我們談談當時
...you got from top administration officials.
你了解的几位高官的反應
On that day, what did the president say to you?
在那天，總統跟你說了些什么？
The president, in a very intimidating way, left me and my staff...
總統，用一種很強迫性的口吻， 向我和我的同事們明確暗示
...with the clear indication he wanted us to come back...
要一口咬定911事件背后
...with the word that there was an Iraqi hand behind 9/11.
是伊拉克在操縱的
They planned to do something about Iraq before they came into office.
他們還未當政之前就計划 要對伊拉克下手了
Did he ask about any other nations other than Iraq?
他問到過伊拉克以外的國家了嗎？
No, not at all. It was, "Iraq, Saddam, find out, get back to me."
一個也沒有，原話是：“伊拉克、 薩達姆，去查他們，找証據給我”
Were his questions more about Iraq than al Qaeda?
他問得更多的是伊拉克，而不是基地組織？
Absolutely. He didn't ask me about al Qaeda.
一點沒錯，他根本沒向我 問起過基地組織
And the reaction you got from the defense secretary, Rumsfeld...
你了解的國防部長拉姆斯費爾德和
...from his assistant, Paul Wolfowitz?
他的副手沃爾福威茨的反應呢？
Donald Rumsfeld said... When we talked about bombing...
當我們在談到要轟炸基地組織
...the al Qaeda infrastructure in Afghanistan...
在阿富汗的基地時
...he said, "There are no good targets in Afghanistan.
他說阿富汗有什么好炸的
Let's bomb Iraq."
我們炸伊拉克吧
And we said, "But Iraq had nothing to do with this."
于是我們說：“但伊拉克和這毫不相干啊”
That didn't make much difference. The reason they had...
但這沒起什么作用， 他們先打阿富汗的原因是
...to do Afghanistan first was, it was obvious al Qaeda attacked us.
基地組織攻擊了我們，這很明顯
And it was obvious that al Qaeda was in Afghanistan.
此外，基地組織位于阿富汗，這也很明顯
Americans wouldn't stand by if we'd done nothing on Afghanistan.
如果我們對阿富汗不聞不問， 美國人是不答應的
The United States began bombing Afghanistan...
９１１之后的第４個星期 美國對阿富汗展開轟炸-
...just four weeks after 9/11. Mr. Bush said he was doing so...
布什說他這樣做是因為
...because the Taliban government of Afghanistan...
阿富汗的塔利班政權
...had been harboring bin Laden.
在庇護本﹒拉登
We will smoke them out of their holes.
我們要把他們從洞穴里熏出來
We're gonna smoke them out.
我們要把他們熏出來
- We'll smoke him out of his cave. - Let's rush them and smoke them out.
我們要把他熏出來 我們追他，把他們熏出來
For all his tough talk, Bush really didn't do much.
說得很強硬，但布什卻沒什么行動
Well, what they did was slow and small.
他們行動又緩慢又微不足道
They put only 11,000 troops into Afghanistan.
他們只往阿富汗派了1.1萬人
There are more police here in Manhattan.
曼哈頓的警察都比這多
More in Manhattan than there are U.S. Troops in Afghanistan.
曼哈頓的警察比阿富汗的美軍都多
The president botched the response. He should have gone after bin Laden.
總統的應對很拙劣 他本應抓住本﹒拉登的
The U.S. Special Forces didn't get into the area where bin Laden was...
美軍特種部隊在整整兩個月的時間內
...for two months. - Two months?
沒有進入本﹒拉登的藏身地區 兩個月？
A mass murderer who attacked the United States...
一個謀殺了這么多美國人的凶手
...was given a two-month head start?
被給了2個月的時間做准備
Who in their right mind would do that?
哪個正常人會那樣做？
- Dang! Anybody say "nice shot"? - Nice shot.
沒人喝個彩？ 射的不錯
Hell of a shot.
真不錯
Or was the war in Afghanistan really about something else?
也許阿富汗戰爭另有目的？
Perhaps the answer was in Houston, Texas.
也許答案就在德州的休斯頓
In 1997, while George W. Bush was governor of Texas...
1997年，當喬治﹒布什還是德州州長時 -
...a delegation of Taliban leaders from Afghanistan flew to Houston...
塔利班的一個代表團從 阿富汗飛到休斯頓
...to meet with Unocal executives...
來會見Unocal公司的總裁
...to discuss the building of a pipeline through Afghanistan...
討論在阿富汗境內修建一條輸油管道
...bringing natural gas from the Caspian Sea.
將里海的天然氣運出來
And who got a Caspian Sea drilling contract...
在Unocal公司簽訂了輸油管合同的當天
...the same day Unocal signed the pipeline deal?
是誰得到了里海油田的開采合同？
A company headed by a man named Dick Cheney. Halliburton.
是一個叫迪克﹒切尼－赫利波頓的公司
From the point of view of the U.S. Government...
在美國政府看來 （此人為Unocal公司顧問）
...this was kind of a magic pipeline...
這是條有魔力的輸油管
...because it could serve so many purposes.
因為它能達到多重目的
And who else stood to benefit from the pipeline?
其他還有誰能從輸油管中獲利呢？
Bush's number-one campaign contributor, Kenneth Lay...
那是布什最重要的競選贊助人－－
...and the good people of Enron.
安龍公司的大財主肯尼斯﹒雷
Only the British press covered this trip.
只有英國媒體報道了這次來訪
Then in 2001, just five and a half months before 9/11...
后來在2001年，911之前的5個半月
...the Bush administration welcomed a Taliban envoy...
布什政府邀請一位塔利班特使
...to tour the United States...
來訪問美國各地
...to help improve the image of the Taliban government.
以幫助塔利班政權改善形象
You have imprisoned the women. It's a horror, let me tell you.
你們是在囚禁婦女，這太恐怖了
I'm sorry to your husband. He must have a difficult time with you.
我為你丈夫感到難過， 他和你相處，一定很不開心
Here is the Taliban official visiting our State Department...
這是塔利班特使拜訪國務院
...to meet with U.S. Officials.
與美國官員會面
Why would the Bush administration allow a Taliban leader...
為什么布什當局會允許一個 塔利班官員
...to visit the United States, knowing that the Taliban...
來訪問美國，明知道他們
...were harboring the man who bombed the U.S.S. Cole...
庇護著炸掉科爾號軍艦
...and our African embassies?
和我們駐非洲使館的凶手？
Well, I guess 9/11 put a stop to that.
我想９１１事件給這關系畫上了句號
When the invasion of Afghanistan was complete...
占領阿富汗之后
...we installed its new president, Hamid Karzai.
我們立了個新總統，卡爾扎伊
Who was Hamid Karzai?
誰是卡爾扎伊？
He was a former adviser to Unocal.
他是Unocal公司的前顧問
Bush also appointed, as our envoy to Afghanistan...
布什任命的我們駐阿富汗特使
...Zalmay Khalilzad, who was also a former Unocal adviser.
哈利扎巴德，他同樣也是Unocal公司 的前顧問
I guess you can probably see where this is leading.
你大概已經知道這是怎么一回事了吧
Faster than you can say, "Black gold, Texas tea, " Afghanistan signed...
比你說“黑金，德克薩斯州來了”還快
...an agreement with her neighboring countries...
阿富汗就和鄰國簽約
...to build a pipeline carrying natural gas from the Caspian Sea.
建造一條將天然氣從里海運出來的輸油管
Oh, and the Taliban?
那么塔利班去哪了？
Oh, they mostly got away.
哦，他們大部分都溜掉了
As did Osama bin Laden and most of al Qaeda.
奧薩馬﹒本﹒拉登和大部分基地組織也溜掉了
T error is bigger than one person.
恐怖不是他一個人造成的
And he's a person who's now been marginalized.
再說他也游走不定
So I don't know where he is.
所以我不知道他在哪
I just don't spend that much time on him, to be honest with you.
老實說，我沒在他身上下太多工夫
Didn't spend much time on him? What kind of president was he?
沒在他身上下太多工夫？ 他是怎樣當總統的啊？
I'm a war president. I make decisions here in the Oval Office...
我是戰時的總統，我在 白宮的總統辦公室做決策
...in foreign policy matters with war on my mind.
決定對外政策， 戰爭都在我考慮中
With the war in Afghanistan over and bin Laden forgotten...
隨著阿富汗戰爭結束，本﹒拉登被人遺忘
...the war president had a new target:
戰時總統又有了一個新目標：
The American people.
美國人民
We've got an unusual terror warning from the feds to tell you about.
我們從聯邦政府處得到 不同尋常的恐怖襲擊警告
Fox News has obtained an FBI bulletin...
福克斯新聞台從聯邦調查局處得到報告
...that warns terrorists could use pen guns, like in James Bond...
警告說恐怖分子有可能使用 鋼筆式手槍，就像詹姆斯﹒邦德使用的那種
...filled with poison. - Good evening.
子彈還帶毒呢 晚上好
America is on high alert tonight, just four days before Christmas.
在聖誕節前僅僅4天，美國今晚 處于高度警戒狀態
- A possible terror threat. - As bad as or worse than 9/11.
很有可能的恐怖威脅 有可能比911事件還嚴重
But where? How? There's nothing specific to report.
但是恐怖襲擊發生在哪里？怎樣襲擊？ 沒有詳情可供報道
Be on the lookout for model airplanes packed with explosives.
要警惕裝有炸彈的遙控模型飛機
The FBI is warning ferries may be considered particularly at risk...
聯邦調查局警告各航班處于
...for hijacking.
被劫機的極度危險中
Could these cattle be a target for terrorists?
這些牲口會成為恐怖分子的目標嗎？
- Fear works. - Fear does work, yes.
恐懼開始彌漫 是的，恐怖的確開始彌漫
You can make people do anything if they're afraid.
如果人們害怕的話，你可以讓他們做任何事
And how do you make them afraid?
那怎樣能讓他們害怕呢
Well, you make them afraid by creating an aura of endless threat.
我們制造一種持續不斷的恐怖氣氛 以使他們害怕
They played us like an organ.
他們把我們玩弄于股掌之間
They raised the orange, up to red, then they dropped it back to orange.
他們把國家安全警報從橙色調高到紅色， 再調回到橙色
I mean, they gave these mixed messages, which were crazy-making.
他們制造一些含混的信息， 簡直要讓人發瘋了
The world is changed after September the 11th.
９１１之后，世界變了
It's changed because we're no longer safe.
世界變了，因為我們不再安寧
Fly and enjoy America's great destination spots.
坐飛機來享受美國的名勝吧
We have entered what may prove to be the most dangerous...
我們已處在也許是 前所未有嚴重的
...security environment the world's known.
安全環境中
Take your families and enjoy life.
帶上你的家人來享受生活吧
Terrorists are doing everything they can...
恐怖分子用盡一切可能
...to gain even deadlier means of striking us.
來攻擊我們
- Go down to Disney World in Florida. - It's like training a dog.
來佛羅里達州的迪斯尼樂園吧！ 這就像在訓練一條狗
You tell him sit down and roll over at the same time, dog doesn't know...
你讓它同時又要坐著，又要打滾 狗不知道該做哪樣
...what to do. American people were being treated like that.
美國民眾就是這樣地被對待
It was very, very skillfully and ugly, in what they did.
他們這么做，即巧妙，又丑惡
We must stop the terror.
我們必需阻止恐怖主義
I call upon all nations to do everything they can to stop these terrorist killers.
我呼吁所有國家盡全力 阻止這些恐怖主義殺人犯
Thank you.
謝謝
Now watch this drive.
看看這一杆
All right. You give me another one.
很好，他又打中一杆
They will continue, in my view, as long as this administration is in charge...
我想只要他們還在當政
...of every once in a while, stimulating everybody to be afraid.
他們會時不時刺激一下每個人， 讓他們害怕
Just in case you forgot.
使他們不能忘記
It's not gonna go down to green or blue. It's never gonna get there.
警告顏色是永不會降到綠色或藍色的
There clearly is no way that anyone...
很明顯地，沒有人能老是
...can live constantly on edge like that.
在這種懸崖邊緣中活下去
The reality facing American families...
美國家庭今天所面對的嚴酷現實
...is they're not as safe as they used to be.
就是他們不再像以前那樣安全了
Drug dealers and users looking for their next fix.
毒販或吸毒者都在找下一個獵物
Gangs who roam the streets in search of their next victim.
流氓團伙在街上找他們的下一個犧牲品
And the growing threat of terrorists means the need for protection...
還有與日俱增的恐怖襲擊威脅， 使得防護需求
...is ever greater. And now that protection is here.
前所未有地高漲 現在，這種防護設備出現了
Zytech Engineering, LLC has developed and tested a safe room...
Zytech公司，終于研發了一種
...finally affordable to the average American citizen.
美國普通老百姓能買得起的安全屋
Protection formerly obtainable only by the wealthy or powerful.
以前只有有錢人或者高官才 會有正規的防護措施
Heck, you can be sitting in here, drinking your finest Bordeaux...
你可以坐在這里喝著上好的 波爾多葡萄酒
...and enjoying life, while chaos is erupting outside.
享受人生，哪怕外面洪水滔天
Every family in America should prepare itself...
所有美國家庭都應
...for a terrorist attack.
為可能的恐怖襲擊作准備
Now to escaping from a skyscraper. John Rivers is the CEO...
怎樣從高樓大廈逃脫， 降落傘公司的執行總裁約翰.里弗斯
...of the Executive Chute Corporation. Good morning to you, John.
來到了我們的節目 早上好，約翰
- Good morning, Matt. - Tell me about the product.
早上好，馬特 介紹一下你們准備上市的產品
It's an emergency escape chute. It's an option of last resort.
這是緊急逃脫降落傘， 是我們最后的逃脫手段
How high do you have to be in the building...
這降落傘能在多高
...for that chute to actually take effect?
打開？
You only have to be on the 10th floor or above.
只要是１０樓或以上就可以
They can put this on themselves?
他們自己單獨可以穿上嗎？
Right. They can put this on themselves in as easy...
是的，他們自己可以很容易地穿上
...as about 30 seconds. It's real easy to put on.
３０秒就足夠了 非常容易穿上
- Here. - Sorry.
這樣
That's okay. Real easy to put on, but...
沒關系，真的很容易穿 但是
When you first get this chute, you're gonna wanna put it on...
你拿到產品之后， 應該在用之前練習穿几次
...and try it on a few times yourself. - Jaime's having trouble putting that on.
杰美穿這個有些費勁啊
Is this something that you honestly think, in a moment of panic...
打斷一下，如果在恐慌的情形下
...that someone can operate properly?
還能正確穿上嗎？
Oh, yeah. It is. This is actually... Jamie's probably never...
嗯，當然 杰美大概是
...put this thing on before in her life.
從未穿過這東西
It's okay. It's something that, when you get it...
沒關系
...you're gonna wanna put it on several times.
當你剛買到這產品就應先試几次
Despite the raising of the terror alert level, residents here continue...
雖然恐怖警戒級別在升高，薩吉諾的居民 （薩吉諾：密歇根州東部的港口）
...with their Christmas errands.
還是在接著進行聖誕采購
Frances and her family do some last-minute holiday shopping...
弗朗西斯和她的家人知道基地組織 正籌划襲擊
...knowing al Qaeda is planning to attack.
他們還是在進行聖誕節前的最后一次采購
She says being in Saginaw doesn't make her feel any safer...
她說她住在薩吉諾
...than if she was in New York City.
并不覺得比在紐約安全
Midland is close by...
米德蘭（密歇根城市）就在附近
...and I said, "Detroit's not that far away."
底特律也不是很遠
I said, "That could be something... And Flint could be something... Be...
弗林特（密歇根城市）也不遠
...concerns for people around here." - You never know...
這里的人們也可能成為襲擊目標
...where they're gonna hit. Never know.
你永遠也不會知道他們准備要襲擊哪里 永遠也不會
But one potential target specifically mentioned by the terrorists...
但有一處恐怖分子特別提到過
...has security officials baffled. It's tiny Tappahannock, Virginia...
而安全部門又未加強防護的潛在襲擊地點， 那是弗吉尼亞州的塔帕漢洛克
...population, 2016.
人口2016人
Such an attack could generate widespread fear...
這種襲擊會產生散播恐懼
...that even here in rural, small-town America, no one is entirely safe.
即就算是這種鄉下的美國小鎮， 也不是絕對安全的
On the news there was an alert in Tappahannock.
早間新聞上說塔帕漢洛克正處于 恐怖主義威脅中
- What did the FBI tell you? - Well, they contacted me by phone.
聯邦調查局跟你說了些什么？ 嗯他們給我打了電話，說：
Basically let me know about this, were it Tappahannock.
嗯，首先告訴我，是塔帕漢洛克嗎？
- That's how it started. - In the so-called chatter they pick up...
電話就是這樣開頭的， 他們喋喋不休地說起
...they wasn't sure Tappahannock. There's a Rappahannock County...
他們不清楚塔帕漢洛克 有個縣叫拉帕漢洛克
...Rappahannock River. - There is a Rappahannock...
還有拉帕漢洛克河 有個叫拉帕漢洛克的地方
A place called Rappahannock. They got it mixed up.
拉帕漢洛克，他們搞昏了頭
This is Tappahannock, not Rappahannock.
這里是塔帕漢洛克，不是拉帕漢洛克
- Is there any target around here? - Not that we can think of.
這里有任何恐怖分子想要襲擊的目標嗎 我們想不出有什么
- It can happen anywhere. - Wal-Mart.
哪里都有可能 沃爾瑪超市
A big spaghetti supper in here.
還有這里那家大的意大利面館
Wal-Mart, probably.
可能是沃爾瑪吧
Do you feel extra suspicious of outsiders?
有留意過什么特別可疑的外人嗎-
Oh, everybody does that.
這所有人都有在留意
That's just something that happens.
情況就是這樣
When I look at certain people, I wonder, "Oh, my goodness.
當我看到某人，我就在想，天哪
Do you think they could be a terrorist?"
那可能就是恐怖分子嗎？
- Never know what's gonna happen. - Right.
不知道會發生什么事？ 對
It could happen right now.
可能立刻就出事了
Never trust nobody you don't know.
永遠不會相信陌生人
And even if you do know them, you really can't trust them then.
即使認識他，也不敢真的相信他
From Tappahannock to Rappahannock...
從塔帕漢諾克到拉帕漢諾克
...to every town and village in America, the people were afraid.
美國每個鄉村、小鎮， 人們都處在恐慌中
And they turned to their leader to protect them.
于是人民尋求領袖來保護他們
But protect them from what?
但是，保護他們提防誰呢？
Meet John Ashcroft.
認識一下約翰﹒ 阿什克羅夫特吧
In 2000, he was running for re-election as senator for Missouri...
2000年，他作為密蘇里州參議員 再次參選國會議員
...against a man who died the month before the election.
對手在選舉前一個月就去世了
The voters preferred the dead guy.
結果選民選了那個死人
So George W. Bush made him his attorney general.
于是布什任命他做司法部長
He was sworn in on a stack of Bibles.
他在聖經面前庄嚴發誓
Because when you can't beat a dead guy...
因為當你斗不過死人
...you need all the help you can get.
你就得爭取一切東西來幫你
During the summer before 9/11...
在911之前的那個夏天
...Ashcroft told acting FBI director, Thomas Pickard...
阿什克羅夫特告訴聯邦調查局 的代理局長 托馬斯﹒皮卡德
...that he didn't want to hear anything more about terrorist threats.
他不想再聽到任何有關恐怖主義 威脅的聒噪
Mr. Watson had come to you and said that the CIA was very concerned...
沃森先生來跟你說中情局
...that there would be an attack.
非常關注潛在的恐怖襲擊
You said that you told the attorney general this fact repeatedly...
你說，你在很多次會面中
...in these meetings. That correct?
反復告誡過司法部長這個事實 對嗎？
I've told him at least on two occasions.
我至少在兩個場合告訴他此事 （前聯邦調查局代理局長，皮卡德）
And you told the staff, according to this statement...
根據這份証詞， 你對你的部下說
...Mr. Ashcroft told you that he did not want to hear about this anymore.
阿什克羅夫特先生對你說他 再不想多聽到這事
- Is that correct? - That is correct.
是嗎？ 是的
His own FBI knew that summer there were al Qaeda members...
他手下的聯邦調查局在那個夏天就得知 有基地成員在美國境內
...in the U.S. And bin Laden was sending his agents to flight schools...
而且本﹒拉登正派人到
...around the country.
國內各地的飛行學校去
But Ashcroft's Justice Department turned a blind eye...
但是阿什克羅夫特的司法部門 對此視而不見
...and a deaf ear.
充耳不聞
But after 9/11, John Ashcroft had some brilliant ideas...
但是在911之后，阿什克羅夫特
...for how to protect America.
就如何保護美國有了個絕妙的點子
The Patriot Act, adopted by Congress and signed by Bush...
在恐怖襲擊的６個星期后， 愛國法案經國會通過
...six weeks after the attacks...
并被布什簽署生效
...has changed the way the government does business.
這改變了政府辦事的方式
The Patriot Act allows for searches of medical and financial records...
愛國法案允許政府搜查公民的 醫療和財務記錄
...computer and telephone conversations...
以及電腦、通話
...even for the books you take out of the library. But people we spoke to...
甚至你從圖書館借書的記錄 但是我們采訪的人，大部分都說
...say they're willing to give up liberties to fight terrorism.
為和恐怖主義做斗爭， 他們愿意放棄一些自由權利
- Maybe that's a good thing. - It's sad, but it has to be done.
也許那是好事 當然有些失落，但必須這么做
Yes, something needed to be done.
是的，有些事情必須這么做
These are the good people who make up Peace Fresno.
這群好公民是弗雷斯諾和平會的會員
A community group in Fresno, California.
位于加利福尼亞州弗雷斯諾市 的社區團體
Unlike the rest of us, they received an early lesson...
不像我們，他們較早就開始
...in what the Patriot Act is all about.
學習討論愛國法案的內容
Each week, they meet to discuss matters of peace.
每個星期，他們聚在一起 討論有關和平的事情
They sit around, they share stories, they eat cookies.
他們坐在一起，分享故事，一起吃曲奇餅
Some have more than one.
有些人還吃了不止一塊
This is Aaron Stokes, a member of Peace Fresno.
這位是亞倫.斯托克斯 弗雷斯諾和平會的會員
The other members liked him.
其他會員都喜歡他
He had come to the meetings, he went with us.
他來參加會議，跟我們聚會
We go out on Friday nights and stand on a very busy corner in Fresno.
每星期五的晚上和我們一起 站在弗雷斯諾繁忙的街頭散發傳單
And he had gone with us, he had handed out fliers.
他和我們一起散發文件
He went with us in June to a WTO protest.
在６月跟我們一起 去抗議世界貿易組織的會議
Then one day, Aaron didn't show up to the meeting.
后來有一天，亞倫沒有來參加會議
My friend Dan and I were reading the Sunday newspaper...
我朋友丹娜和我正在讀星期天的報紙
...and when I picked up the paper, in the local section...
當我拿起報紙， 看到地方新聞上
...Aaron's picture caught my eye.
有亞倫的照片
The article said that a sheriff's deputy had been killed...
那篇報道說有地方警員被殺
...and I saw it had a name that wasn't the right name...
我看到他的名字并不是我們知道的那個名字
...that said that he was a member of the sheriff's antiterrorism unit.
報道說他是警局反恐小組的成員
That's right.
沒錯
The photo of the man in the newspaper...
報紙上的照片
...was not the Aaron Stokes they had come to know.
不是他們認識的亞倫.斯托克斯
He was actually Deputy Aaron Kilner, and he had infiltrated their group.
他實際上是特工亞倫﹒金勒， 他滲透到他們的團體中了
Sheriff Pierce made it very clear that, yes...
皮爾斯警官說得很明白了，是的
...Aaron Kilner was assigned to infiltrate Peace Fresno...
亞倫﹒金勒受命潛入到弗雷斯諾和平會中
...that he was able to infiltrate organizations...
他是為了潛入
...that are open to the public.
公共團體而來的
You could understand why the police needed to spy...
你也許明白為什么警察要偵察
...on a group like Peace Fresno.
弗雷斯諾和平會這樣的團體
Just look at them.
只是要監視他們
A gathering of terrorists if I ever saw one.
如果說我見過恐怖分子集會的話， 這算一個吧
This is Barry Reingold, a retired phone worker...
這位是巴里.雷哥德， 加利福尼亞州奧肯市的
...from Oakland, California.
退休電話工人
Barry likes to work out in the gym.
巴里喜歡到健身房做運動
Somewhere between his cardio and his strength training...
在健身器械堆中的某處
...Barry got political.
巴里談到了政治
We were up in the gym, and it was after we were working out...
我們在做完運動后， 我們聚集一起
...and a number of us were talking about 9/11 and Afghanistan...
談論９１１、阿富汗
...and bin Laden, and someone said, "Bin Laden's a real asshole...
和本﹒拉登，有個人說： 本﹒拉登真是個混蛋
...for murdering those people." And I said, "Yeah, that's true.
殺了那么多人“ 我說：”沒錯
But he'll never be as big an asshole as Bush...
但是他還沒有像布什那樣混帳
...who bombs all over the world for oil profits."
為了石油利益轟炸世界各地
Barry didn't have to worry about the police spying on him.
巴里本不用擔心警察會監視他
His fellow weightlifters were more than willing to turn him in.
他的健身伙伴把他給舉報了
I was taking a nap, and I guess it was 1:30, 2:00 in the afternoon.
我正在午睡，大概是下午1點半，或者是2點
And they came to my place, and I said, "Well, who's there?"
他們來到我家找我 我問道：“誰啊？”
And they said, "The FBI." I said, "The FBI? Why are they here?"
他們說：“ＦＢＩ” 我說：“FBI？為什么跑這里來了？”
Yes, the FBI had come to see Barry. And they weren't there to Jazzercise.
是的，ＦＢＩ來找巴里了，他們可不是 去找他玩爵士樂的
The FBI said, "Have you been talking to people about 9/11 and bin Laden...
FBI說：你和別人在討論911和本﹒拉登
...and oil profits and Afghanistan?" I said, "A lot of people are talking...
還有石油利益和阿富汗嗎？“ 我說：”很多人都在
...about these things."
討論這個話題啊
I feel my rights have been, you know, trampled on.
我感覺我的權利被踐踏了
I mean, if you have something to say to me in the gym, well, then, fine.
我是說，如果你有事想在健身房里跟我說， 這沒關系
Don't tell the FBI, and they come to my apartment while I'm taking a nap.
但別告訴FBI，他們會在我睡覺的時候 找到我的公寓來的